### Contact

csmith1729@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/craigsmith-96661771 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Hospitals Nursing Critical Care

Certifications
CCRN Alum

#### Honors-Awards

Undergraduate Professor of the Year South Carolina Palmetto Gold Award

# **Craig Smith**

Director Of Education at Kingman Regional Medical Center Kingwood, Texas

## Summary

Focused transformational leader. Enjoy research and believe it should drive clinical decisions. Strong follower of servant leadership and live by the motto, "visibility breads credibility and credibility breads trust." Currently the Director of Education at KIngwood Medical Center. Prior experience as Director of Education and Research at Providence Hospitals. I have directed a million dollar simulation lab and administered Learning Management Systems. Also have prior experience as Faculty at the University of South Carolina College of Nursing where I was the course coordinator for both junior and senior Med-Surg. courses. Additionally I work part time as online faculty at Grand Canyon University where I teach RN to BSN students. I have a Masters (MSN) in Nursing Informatics with a focus on Clinical Education and Work Flow Logistics.

# Experience

Kingman Regional Medical Center Director Of Education June 2019 - Present (1 year)

Kingwood Medical Center
Director of Education
June 2017 - June 2019 (2 years 1 month)
Kingwood, Texas

East Cooper Medical Center
Director Of Education
April 2016 - June 2017 (1 year 3 months)
Mt. Pleasant, SC

Small hospital with focus on orthopedic and women's services.

Providence Hospitals
Director of Clinical Education and Research
May 2013 - April 2016 (3 years)

Oversee all clinical education for both hospitals. Responsible for all regulatory compliance as related to clinical competencies. DNV and ISO compliance.

University of South Carolina Clinical Instructor August 2011 - May 2013 (1 year 10 months)

Course coordinator for Med Surg course 411 and 412. Assistant professor in Foundations course.

Lexington Medical Center RN 2005 - 2009 (4 years) ICU

## Education

Walden University

Master of Science in Nursing, Nursing Informatics · (2009 - 2011)

University of South Carolina Upstate
Bachelor of Science (BS), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2003 - 2005)